all right well you know you guys are
stuck with me again for for better or
worse so hopefully you guys will find
this helpful
so I've tried to structure it is kind of
like a mixed talk where I'm gonna both
walk you through some paradigms and some
empirical results from those paradigms
and then that are based on modeling and
then I'll walk you through putting
together the actual models for those
tasks you first get to see why it's
useful and what the results that can
come out of it look like and then
hopefully you'll be even more motivated
to know how to do it um so so I sent out
a few MATLAB example MATLAB scripts and
so they are they were definitely in an
email that everyone should have gotten
if you haven't downloaded them then I'm
sorry if there's a way you can still get
access to them via the internet or
whatever that I hope you can otherwise
I'll show everything up on up on here I
have MATLAB I have the scripts open and
if you do have the scripts open right
now don't look at them yet
I specifically don't want you to have
gone through them before because means
you'll have the answers to some things
ahead of time where I want you to try to
come up with them on the fly as we build
stuff so okay um so general a line like
I said so I'll give you some task
descriptions and some preliminary
empirical results from fitting models to
behavior from people that have done
these tasks and a bunch of different and
healthy and a bunch of different
clinical populations and there's there's
three of them there's this approach
avoidance conflict task which is what
I'll probably spend most of the time I'm
kind of building the model in detail and
hope is that that'll give you kind of a
thorough sense so then I'll walk you
through the next task then we can kind
of go through the model or briefly and
hopefully it'll just if even if we don't
walk through it in as much detail for
the latter ones I'm hoping that'll sort
of enforce some kind of generalization
and so you can see how it's not just how
the kind of general abstract structure
of these is actually very similar across
specific models you go and
and so actually the way I've kind of
depicted this is a little bit wrong it's
for each of these I'm gonna give you
some what with different levels of
detail and kind of hands-on tutorial
where we'll build the models will
simulate some outputs I'll make sure you
guys have some sense how to interpret
the simulation plots which are honestly
not all that straightforward always in M
papers by Carl & Co and and then I'll
actually even show you a little bit
about how to estimate parameters so to
actually get individual difference
parameter estimates for each person
who's done the task and so at least you
know I'm not I'm not saying you'll walk
away with this being able to do
absolutely everything without any
further help but it should give you a
good sense of the process and give you
kind of the resources to you know
practice and move from here and I'm
happy to answer any questions or go
through further things after its some
other point during the week so oh and
then and then additionally it occurred
to me near the end that not most of this
is much more inference based as opposed
to learning based and active learning is
certainly a really important part of
active inference especially when you're
doing learning tasks and so there's a
little bit of that 3m bandit that I'll
go over with you in a couple of slides
mainly to give you guys a sense of how
you would do something like reward
learning um inactive inference and how
you kind of think about it okay it gets
cast a little bit differently and then I
might also walk you through some of the
additional kind of simulation paper that
we have a free printout on right now on
how to use active influence for
structure learning which is more or less
just an extension of the way you do
active learning but I think it's a
little bit more illustrative of how of
how learning parameters I'm actually
works with these models so we'll see
what we get there and depends on how
long some of this takes so okay so first
the approach avoidance conflict task so
so it's approach avoidance conflict and
basically this is something that happens
it's a big problem in psychopathology
especially in emotional disorders is
that a lot of times you have to choose
to approach a situation when both some
bats
and some good stuff will happen at the
same time or you can avoid the bad stuff
and go do something safe but that means
you actually sacrifice a lot of the good
stuff you would have gotten as well and
so oftentimes what happens in the
context of anxiety and depression is
that you'll kind of actually end up
sacrificing a lot of good things a lot
of sort of well-being promoting
activities in life due to a kind of fear
of the inability to handle some of the
possible negative outcomes that you'd
get as well so the and this is a primary
target of a lot of interventions both
cognitive behavioral and other and
basically most likely therapeutic
interventions in one way or another
target us and so the and this applies
for instance in depression and anxiety
and you know it can be things like
avoiding social activities because of
fear of judgment or embarrassment in
substance use disorders it could be like
drug taking to avoid withdrawal symptoms
things like that we're just avoidance is
a big is a big thing and and so people
have come up with these these tasks that
are supposed to mimic having to sort of
deal with that kind of conflict and so
I'll tell you about one specific
approach avoidance conflict task that we
have used and how we how you can build a
model of it the data so this this
particular study and the other ones I'll
talk about - all come from this fairly
large data set and we've collected in in
Tulsa liber where I am where I work and
called the t1000 this specifically from
the first 500 participants of the t1000
it's essentially the exploratory half of
a larger exploratory confirmatory sort
of study approach that we've been taking
and and so for this 500 this is just
kind of like a quasi consort diagram but
more or less what we end up with is 59
healthy controls 261 people that have
depression and/or anxiety so this is
really meant to be much for kind of
trans diagnostic and some kind of our
document
and sort of and then we also have 159 in
substance use group which is largely
methamphetamine but there is also some
opioid and some other ones in there so
it's and I should say these this group
also can have a bunch of anxiety and
depression in it so it's really not
meant to be displaying diagnostically
carved-up example so okay so the
approach avoidance conflict task
basically the way that it works is
you're shown a little avatar guy like
this and you're on this kind of runway
and it has one of nine positions and
your job is to choose where you want to
move this avatar to now the kind of
happy son picture over there that stands
in for seeing a kind of mildly positive
safe stimulus and whereas the kind of
rainy cloud that means that you are
going to see a fairly strongly negative
stimulus but you'll also win a certain
amount of points where this kind of
little gauge here tells you how many
points and it can be filled either to
two points four points or six points and
so and the idea is that each one of
these different positions carries a
different probability of getting that
outcome or that outcome so basically if
you're all the way to the right that
means it's 90 percent chance you'll get
this guy ten percent that you'll get
that guy 80 70 60 50 40 etc so the more
you're over here the higher the chance
you're gonna get the safe some thing
more over here the higher the chance
you're gonna get the rainy cloud
endpoints thing but it's not fully
deterministic visibly that's one of the
negative stimuli that you'll get if you
uh if you go for the points so point
being these are legit aversive you know
to the to the degree that you can get
through IRB so so you know it's not we
turned our best to make it so it's not
just these purely kind of you know my
negative you know you can rate it but
you don't still have that much of a
reaction etc but then you get this nice
happy you made points right so so there
hence the conflict um so but say instead
so I should say it's a different trial
they're different trial types different
conditions where you know the rainy
cloud over here Sun over here you know
zero points or two points etc I'll show
you the different conditions in a second
but so say instead you get try to go for
the safe thing then there's your so
there's your happy safe though and this
is really just meant to be kind of like
an anchor right like an anchor kind of
safe you go to it if you are too afraid
of the negative thing to get the points
more or less right you made zero points
okay so here's the five different task
conditions in this case so one we just
call avoid threat basically there's just
rainy cloud and Sun there's no points
involved it's a really you ought to just
just all the way over here every time um
in this case it's the approach reward
condition there's both full Suns on both
sides but you get points over here so
again it should just be move all the way
the right please you're doing and then
there's conflict two points conflict
four and conflict six in which case it's
either the Sun or rainy cloud plus
certain amount of points
um again two four six so those are the
different conditions so the again we're
gonna walk through this in a lot of
detail but the way that we set up the
model for this the exact same structure
as what I showed you guys yesterday
hopefully some of you still remember a
little but city it is you have some
prior preferences up here the C thing
and there are two parameters that we fit
for this essentially it's the value that
the the agent assigns to the negative
stimuli so essentially how much it
dislikes the negative stimulant and then
this VP thing which is the value at
aside the subjective value assigned to
each point you could win and so and so
these two things essentially control
ought to govern a fair amount of
behavior because the more you dislike
the negative thing
the less points are worth the more
conflict you ought to have any ought to
be driven to you know toward the Sun but
then there's beta so this prior on
expected policy precision and which for
the paper we've just kind of in also
labeled decision uncertainty just to
kind of make it more intuitive to people
who aren't active inference experts and
so we're fitting that as well so it's a
measure essentially of uncertainty or or
the lack of confidence in your on an
action model and in this case because
we're not building in any prior habits
so II is just flat then this more or
less has the effect of making behavior
just look more random just less
deterministic it would be different if
they had strong habits but since since E
is flat then it basically just governs
deterministic versus random sort of less
stable behavior in a sense and the
states here are more or less the agent
has to have beliefs about where it is on
the runway and the agent also has to
know things about what task condition
it's in and policies are pretty
straightforward you can choose to move
to one of any of the places and nine
places on the runway and the actual
observations right so what the agent
needs to observe to figure out the
runway position in the task condition
and to make a decision so there's three
different sets of observations one is
just runway position cues and the other
is the task condition cues so literally
just what you see on the screen and then
three are gonna be observing the outcome
stimuli so the the negative and positive
images and sounds and points so again
pretty simple and just give you a sense
of what the what the a matrices look
like so how you'd actually set this up
and so this is the essentially the
probability of the outcomes given the
different positions you could be in and
when the trial type or the stimulus or
the the trial condition is a particular
condition so in this case it would be
the avoid threat condition so basically
each
here is one of the different possible
positions on the runway and each row is
one of the different combinations of
outcomes they outcome stimuli you could
observe I'm so under the avoid threat
condition essentially the farther you
are to the left the higher the
probability is that you'll see the
negative stimulus and the farther you
are to the right the higher the
probabilities to see the positive
stimulus but the idea is that these
probability distributions differ
depending on which trial type you're in
right so in in in when the trial type is
6 then this joint distribution ends up
looking like the higher the more you are
over here the higher probability is that
you'll see the positive stimulus but the
higher more you are the more you're over
here to the right the higher the
probability that you'll get negative
stimulus plus 6 points
sorry conditions right here oh oh this
yes right so essentially the different
observations that you can make the way
we set it up are just Sun just clouds
Sun plus 2 points clouds plus 2 points
clouds plus 4 points in cloud posix
place okay and then use that scaling
factors essentially that govern how much
the value is the value of those outcomes
are determined by how much you just like
that negatives didn't listen how much
each each point is worth to me so anyway
so yeah and again we'll go through the
model in detail yes the rows are the
different observations that you can get
right so you can observe the negative
stimulus you can observe the positive
stimulus you can observe negative
stimulus plus 4 points or positive
stimulus those two points you know I'm
not showing all of them on every one
just because it's cluttery but across
all of them it's just negative positive
positive plus 2 negative plus 2 and I
get a four negative six Oh
sorry sorry I didn't explain it so that
[Music]
just for convenience in they just turns
I mean this is a bunch of different ways
you could you could choose to model this
task um the easiest way to do it here is
to just give the agent a kind of
starting position
that's not sort of it doesn't represent
any kind of committed position that
you've chosen on the runway and so the
the first column is just kind of this
starting position before you've chosen
one of the nine positions and the first
row then is just the essentially it's
like blank observation before you've
observed where you put the avatar so
again it's it's just this just for
convenience and sorry I should explain
up so then one thing that we did so one
thing that's important to do a lot of
times if you want to try to convince
people that your parameters do your
estimating in a tasks are actually
tracking something interesting or
something useful or something real is to
try to validate it against some other
measures do you think are also going to
be relevant to the constructs that
you're trying to tap into um and so in
this case you know one way to do that is
to ask a bunch of questions about
self-reported experience or
self-reported behavior on the task and
so in this case we just asked them a
bunch of things you know like I found
the positive pictures enjoyable data one
two seven how much do you agree or
disagree I found it difficult to decide
which outcome I wanted I always tried to
move always towards the outcome with the
largest reward the negative pictures
made me feel anxious or uncomfortable
this one
this one about how anxious or
uncomfortable you feel will be a lot of
interest to me later theoretically and
then also you can measure other kind of
standard behavioral things like reaction
times and things like that that don't
technically go into the model so if the
model can say something about reaction
times and they didn't go into the model
then that can also be valid a-and so
just to give you a sense of what this
ends up looking like in terms of the
parameter validation these are just
Pearson correlations for between each of
parameters and all those different
questions we asked and also with average
reaction times and we actually got you
know pretty much what you would hope for
in a lot of cases so the more you value
subjectively valued the points the
stronger your self-reported drive to
approach with reward was the less
difficulty deciding you had the less you
avoided punishment the faster your
reaction times were etc whereas beta the
more kind of uncertain the more like a
priori unconfident you were in your
action model and so you can think of
that again as a decision uncertainty in
this case was positively associated with
reaction time so the more uncertain you
are the longer it took you to make a
choice and there's a bunch of these
actually they're interesting right like
the more you chose to use certain
negative emotion regulation strategies
for example and probably most
interestingly to me is this guy which
you have to remember at a sample size of
like 500 is actually super significant
is that it wasn't actually the negative
image value or this value in this case
that said much about how anxious or
uncomfortable they self-reported feeling
it was this decision uncertainty
parameter so so what's essentially what
this kind of suggests is that in active
inference the thing that amounts to or
contributes to how subjectively
unpleasant the valence of your status
probably has a lot more to do with how
confident you subjectively think you are
in your action model which again is just
theoretically interesting yeah this is
based on data yeah this is based on the
data into 500 people and so it's just a
parameter that you estimate so in this
case it's largely going to correspond to
something like inconsistency in choices
across trials in the same condition but
kind of it will also be in a way that's
disentangled from
things about say how much you act as
though you value the points and dislike
the negative stimulus right so it's it's
kind of a way of another thing about
modeling in this case is right you can
kind of separate out the estimates of
the most likely contrib relative
contribution of these different sort of
independent psychological factors so
we'll go through the estimation though
but it's just an element in the
parameter that you tweak until the model
generates behavior that looks the most
like the actual participants behavior
and and so then here's some of the
interesting group differences that we
find so when you just break people up
into the healthy controls the people
with depression or anxiety that don't
have substance use and the people with
substance use most of which have either
depression or anxiety and what it turns
out is that actually both of the
clinical groups show greater negative
value assigned to the negative images so
they they're more sensitive essentially
they act as though they expect the
negative stimuli to be more aversive and
in the substance use group they actually
show lower beta values which means that
they are less uncertain so they act more
confident than the healthy people about
what what they think the right thing to
do is so in this case they're more
avoidant and substance use people are
more confident that the avoidance
strategy is right and so it's
interesting there was actually no
difference in the point value subjective
point value and we also found a
difference in prior policy precision
between males and females to where
females actually looked like they had
less confidence in their action model
than men on average they're more
uncertain or you can call that less
impulsive too you know like depends how
you want to spin it so then so that's
kind of just a you know group difference
kind of thing but obviously that's a
little more interesting is whether you
can use this kind of thing to say
something interesting about treatment
outcomes and so here what we did is this
is an eye
I should I didn't I did analyzed the
data and I built the model but this is
data that's being collected largely by a
colleague of mine named Robin a parolee
who's a clinical psychologists at LIBOR
and basically this this study involves a
hundred people that had recruited with
generalized anxiety disorder and they
were then randomized into two groups and
either and one got 10 weeks of exposure
therapy and the other got 10 weeks of
behavioral activation a bunch of these
people also had depression as well as
other anxiety related disorders and so
again somewhat heterogeneous group and
as you can see here response to therapy
was also quite heterogeneous and but on
average both therapies worked and so we
were just interested do each do any of
these 3 parameters that we estimated at
baseline and can they predict anything
about treatment response and pretty cool
what we found is is that it actually
predicts outcomes for both groups so
more or less the the higher your beta
value is so the more uncertain you are
in your action model the better your
response was to both therapies so you
measure this thing at baseline then they
go through the therapy and it turns out
you can sort of say in advance fairly
well who's gonna do better it doesn't
differentiate responders to one
treatment versus the other which is one
thing we were kinda hoping for but it
does say you know is there B gonna work
for you in general relatively speaking
and you know I mean my best way making
sense of this and I should say this this
is for this is based on the promis
depression scale and there was a similar
result for the promis execs go and so
again my best way of making sense of
this at the moment is just to say that
like look if you're a really confident
in your action model and that action
model is avoidance then you probably
gonna be a lot less malleable right give
me less open to trying new behaviors in
therapy and being open to sort of
counter evidence right so so
interestingly the less confident you are
in your action model the more
we are gonna be to update what your
model is about what you should do in
therapy
I'm is kind of that my current sort of
pet interpretation and I should say so
this these results we have a preprint up
on bio archive about right now or
actually it's on if I sell their OSF or
whatever that one is but these we don't
this we don't have anything out on yet
and because we're actually waiting
collect more data to finish it up and
but it's close to being done and so
summary here is that you know it looks
like avoidance in depression anxiety and
substance use looks like it could be
driven by more negative expected
outcomes and greater policy precision
looks like it may indicate greater
confidence in the avoidance strategy in
substance use and the less confident you
are in your avoidance strategy the the
better your you look like you respond to
therapy so and I should say that one
thing when you're building trying to
build a model of something like this
that's worth emphasizing is that there
is no learning in this model and this is
a purely inference based task you know
you know what the stimuli are gonna be
and you just infer okay you know what's
my best bet based on the outcomes I want
to observe based on my relative
preferences about each outcome and the
probabilities and so using something
like I kind of standard reinforcement
learning model that requires you to be
simulating learning doesn't necessarily
work so well whereas active inference is
kind of nice for this because you can do
a purely inference based model um it's
not the only model that can do it but
it's it's a nice feature of active
inference models that you can do that
um okay so now that hopefully I've
motivated why this can be useful let's
let's try to build it and so I showed
you guys briefly how I structured the
model maybe you've forgotten by now but
so kind of just walking through the
logic so let's
you know part one of the model that I
discussed yesterday so just observations
States how states are related
observations and what your prior
expectations over States are so those
are the first four parts right so what
so what are the states is the first
thing that you need to specify when
you're gonna build a model so then the
question is what does the agent need to
know to do the task
so anybody I mean I told you a while ago
but if you don't remember any any any
thoughts as to what what you would need
to know to do it that is one you got to
know where you are to be able to know
where you want to be you know yes you
need to know where you are and yeah the
other places that you could be right so
position on the runway that goes and
it's gonna need to be one hidden state
factor um what else not max well no so
the points aren't actually something
that needs to be hidden state the points
are going to be something that you
observe right they're gonna be an
observation that may or may not be
preferred right so so what else what
else so the image is also going to be an
outcome it's gonna be a thing you
observe the probabilities are going to
be in the a matrix those are the things
that map the states to the observations
values of the points is also an
observation the subjective value of the
points is and that's going to be in the
C matrix which we haven't gotten to yes
trial-type or TAS condition remember cuz
we're you're gonna want to move on the
runway is going to depend on knowing
what condition you're in right so so
those are two things you need to know
where you are on the runway and you got
to know what condition you're what task
condition you're at so minimally a
minimal model of this task requires that
the agent knows those two things and
it's sufficient that it knows those two
things yeah
um yes and in this case they're fairly
trivial it's just what you see on the
screen so there's no uncertainty yeah so
we'll get to that but I mean it's just
an identity matrix it's very yeah any
other questions at this point yeah
um well you won't know where the Sun is
so I mean actually that's that's a good
point
um well interesting yes I agree that if
if no matter what well so that would I
mean that would kind of make you go
wrong in condition to here right because
it's Sun versus Sun plus points and so
in this case if you just had the policy
of always going toward the Sun then you
wouldn't you wouldn't have any idea of
what's on the other side
sure
sure well that's I mean that is about
the negative expected you know negative
value of the outcomes right ahead of
time the governs decision-making and
that is dependent on the context right
that's dependent on the knowing that
they're getting on the train as opposed
to being in some other situation yeah I
mean so in this case I mean point point
totally taken you know in this case I
you know when it comes to the
automaticity of what actions get
selected I mean if remember these I mean
I didn't say that but the it's not as
though the left and right positions of
these are always stable right so I mean
they do flip back and forth and in
counterbalance ways so it can't just be
like I'm always gonna go right I'm
always gonna go left or something like
that right so I mean if it's that that
level of automation that I don't think
it's a problem but but I agree you can
adopt the just play it safe no matter
what sort of strategy which I'll show
you some people behave that way
so which just falls out of the model so
okay so states only position in task
condition all right so um so in practice
in the actual scripts that we'll walk
through in a second and so this is just
a little kind of cut and paste from part
of the script and in practice you
specify the hidden States and the number
of levels teach hidden state by
specifying the D vectors which are your
priors over states and so in this case
and there remember there are two time
points in the trial right there's the
starting point where you make the choice
of what position you're going to go to
and then is the position you go to and
so the D here is your prior over initial
states so um so one then how many
different levels do we need for hidden
state vector 1 which is the positions
anybody so
- nine is what you would think right but
four because of the little a kind of
trick that we used sexually nine plus
one starting positions starting plus the
nine positions you can choose and and
what's the prior what's the prior over
that gonna be yes
exactly yeah exactly wanted a bunch of
zeros you're completely confident that
you're always going to start in the
starting position right that's all that
means
so how about for e to so how many how
many levels are gonna be in that end
state vector there are five yes and what
will the what's what should the prior
look like over that what's the prior
distribution gonna look like yeah so in
this case yes it'll be flat so so in
practice it can just be once I mean this
this is just gonna get normalized so
does it doesn't matter so so just saying
the agent has no prior beliefs that one
task condition is more likely than any
other yeah you could and and for this is
kind of getting the stuff that we'll get
into later worth learning for capital D
makes no difference because it's just
gonna get normalized when it comes to
learning priors which will be little D
then it matters because they stand in
for concentration parameter values but
again everybody ignore that for now okay
so so then so by setting up that that
way you're saying there are ten levels
in hidden state vector one and there are
five levels in ends de factor two and
those are the priors over those levels
okay so then we already kind of talked
about this a little bit but what does
the agent need to see or to observe to
know what state sits in
right so that's gonna be your
observations I already told you but
anyone right so it needs to see this
thing on the screen right it needs to it
needs to see what position it's in
anything else exactly so it needs to see
these cues because those are at what
it's gonna those are what's gonna tell
it what task condition it's in right um
anything else
oh well that's I mean that's just that's
just gonna be part of the cue that tells
you what condition you're in this is
really actually really really obvious
what else does it have to observe yeah
has to observe the the actual outcome
stimuli that it does or does not want to
see and hear right so so so yes so then
those are so those are the three
observation modalities your runaway
position cue is your task condition cues
and what all right whatever that was
okay so so right so runway position cues
task condition cues and outcome stimuli
all right so the idea then is just to
make this clear is that the that those
observations those three sets of
observations are gonna be generated
based on interactions between these two
where you are in these two hidden states
right so for instance being in that
position
combined with being in this condition
will convey a 90 with 90% probability
generate the observation of the negative
stimulus and 6-plus right
the probability is true the agent the
agent knows the probabilities and
they're correct yeah so there's no like
I said this is purely an inference test
there's no wiring okay so in practice
when you look at the script the way that
we set the number of outcomes per out
the modality is just with this kind of
bit of code that more or less just sets
up the a matrix where all its really
doing is it's saying based on D based on
the number of levels in each hidden
state factor make that many columns in
in the a matrix and then for each
outcome modality give it the number of
rows that correspond to the number of
observations for observation modality so
in this case it's just going to be so
you have ten positions right five
conditions because these are just one to
one right you observe the position you
know the position you observe the
condition you know the condition and
then for the stimuli what I showed you
earlier is the way that we chose to do
it is there's seven different formal
observations that could be made in terms
of the signaling go over what oh right
so I will when I go through the images
so so then the a matrix right so the
idea is is that that is explaining how
states generate outcomes which you can
then invert to use for inference so you
observe the outcomes you say conditional
on those outcomes what states am I most
likely in and so here you need one a
matrix per outcome modality so per type
of observation that you can get and so
in this case we'll need three a matrices
one specifying how states generate the
outcome stimuli one specifying how the
states generate condition cues and one
specifying how they state position how
they generate position cues and so
essentially it's just that expanding out
this arrow about how states map to
observations and so here is what the
first a matrix will look like so the one
specifying how states generate outcome
stimuli and so remember here so the way
we've set it up is there are 1 2 3 4 5
ok yeah all right
yes sorry that is my thought so you
should have this one circle as well but
so so there should be 1 2 3 4 5 6
different outcomes you can observe plus
the starting position 1 right so that
corresponds to 7 rows in your a matrix
and so the columns then are each of the
different positions you can be in one
being that starting position and then
each row is going to be one of the
different observation one of their from
observations you could make and then the
entries here and code the probabilities
of observing each outcome given which
state you're in but remember these
distributions are conditional on what
condition you're in right so that's what
this kind of third the third dimension
of this a matrix is is saying
conditional on being in the you know
this condition you know the
probabilities look like that conditional
on being in condition 2 here which is
this guy the probabilities look like
that etc so it's it's encoding these
probabilities again which are known and
then the other ones are really just kind
of trivial right so you can either
observe the cues that you are in the
avoid threat the approach reward the
conflict to for insects and the states
here remember are so are you know this
one stands for being in condition one
condition two condition three etc so
this is just an identity mapping
along the third dimension essentially so
if you observe these cues then no matter
what position on the runway you're in
you're in vehicle you believe you're
gonna believe you're in the avoid avoid
threat condition that that all make
sense if anyone is confused by anything
again this is like for you guys to learn
so we can take like what are way as long
as we need with us very very it's just
saying what you observe tells you with a
hundred percent probability will stay
here at so there's no basically there's
no uncertainty at all and in what you
observe tells you about what's going on
in the task
yes no yeah the partial partially
observable aspect of this doesn't matter
at all for the aspects of the tasks that
don't involve any uncertainty right so
in this case in this case it it's
necessary because of the probabilistic
reward and Punishment outcomes right and
the M I mean yes exactly because that's
for your specifying probabilities right
and equally trivial for position queues
and again it's just it's just saying
it's night any matrix for each of them
so just ones down that I a get all
position equals position right so again
totally trivial but that's the true
psychological ground truth right when
you see the you know where the avatar is
you know where the avatar is okay so any
questions about any of that because the
next thing we'll do is we'll add in the
temporal dimension
chirp-chirp
yeah
formerly it's very easy to do you just
make these things not once the so they
did what the task condition is mm-hmm
mmm miss reading the context cues yeah
absolutely that's actually really
interesting yeah I mean the context of
this task in particular it's probably
yeah you'd have to design a different
task where the context cues are a little
more ambiguous but absolutely yeah and
then formally yeah you just instead of
this just being you know ones you could
just you know make it blurry or and yeah
I mean you'll say I mean obviously like
you know using this again where we're
using models that aren't fully sort of
Bayesian inference based when making
decisions when there's probability is
right like and it's still I mean I still
thought it'd give us interesting results
with the parameters rate but clearly
these models are fancy enough that they
can handle much more difficulty less
problems absolutely
okay so then specifying the B matrix
here
so again conditional on being in state
one how you think you know what your
prior is for what state two is gonna be
or what the state is going to be at time
two that then you're gonna need one B
matrix for each condemned B matrix per
state factor right so basically that's
saying how do you run away positions how
do you believe runway positions are
gonna change over time and how do you
believe that conditions are gonna change
over time within a trial that should be
that needs to be clear because um the
agent is just going to be equipped with
the belief that the
condition is always stable across a
single trial right it's not like the
queues are gonna change as it moves the
avatar but you're gonna need one matrix
for the runway position observation way
up sir runway position state factor but
because this runway position is under
the control of the agent they were
actually going to need to be nine B
matrices for this one B matrix
corresponding to each possible action
that the agent can choose where an
action is here specified as a transition
so so this is important that that well
I'll get to this in a second but
basically what the policies are going to
be when the policy PI thing appears up
here is just selecting one of a bunch of
possible B matrices one of a bunch of
possible transitions that are under the
control of the agent so again trivially
just a little chunk of code here that
just says for condition it's an identity
matrix you know the the task condition
is not going to change while the agents
trying to make a decision about where to
move whereas this the second part here
is just saying that for each of the
different levels in hiddens de factor
one right so ten there's going to be a
bunch of ones for each across one line
for every possible action so at the end
of the day that just looks like this
right so action one so the B matrix one
here action one just basically says no
matter what position you're in if you
choose this B matrix you're gonna
transition to state one so column their
states and rows or states at t plus what
time at the next time point so if you're
in one you move the one if you're in -
you move the one if you're in three you
move to one etc so that's action one
action two is no matter which state
you're in you move to stay - and then
you know dot dot dot until action ten is
no matter what stay here and you move to
say ten
and so each of these is a possible
action that can be chosen each of those
transitions and in this case policies
are going to be identical to actions
because there's just one action it's
just one step but in practice when you
have tasks that require making selecting
sort of chains you know sequences of
actions which is what a policy is
sequence of actions then allowable
policies are going to be allowable sort
of sequences of these right so it can be
like you know be matrix - then B matrix
go on to me matrix three and so forth
and that's why you need a separate you
need to separately specify what the
agent is allowed to do in terms of
allowable policies because maybe you
want to say you know action - 3 - is
allowed but not to - - there's something
like that right so you have to specify
what policies are actually plausible for
the agent to pick windows consists of
different possible sequences of actions
or sequences of transitions that the
agent has control over so in this case
it will just look like this it will just
for the for the second factor so for
condition it's just all it's all just
going to be ones because there is only
one action that can ever be chosen just
stay in the condition but for the runway
position this is saying that the agent
can choose action - or action 3 or
action 4 X + 5 or action 6 7 8 9 or 10
there's no one because one would
correspond to staying in the starting
state which they're not allowed to do
and then again a little snippet of code
for that
mm-hmm yep
mm-hmm
so there are some cases where what looks
like learning can be captured as
inference there are many other cases
where it can't and the particular case
you're talking about I don't think you
can capture that purely as in for
insulation that way is that popping in
mind right now I'm in which case you'd
have to activate the learning component
of these models which I will talk about
a little later but more or less here
just and with each observation so on
each trial you know whatever belief you
or whatever belief you have about what
state you're in
you essentially tack on a count that
says that state is you know that much
more likely because I observed myself
starting in that state in the past or
every time I believe I'm in a certain
state and I observe a certain outcome
then attack on account in the a matrix
that says okay now I believe that that
state can generate that outcome is a
little stronger and so so over time
essentially you're building up priors
about what states you're going to start
in and what states are gonna generate
what observations just through previous
exist through repeated experience it's
essentially it's it centrally just heavy
and just heavy and coincidence learning
and just
mm-hmm
mm-hmm so there are so the reason I said
that is because so one way to model that
is to have different additional
different possible observations where
some observations could involve even
more negative stimuli or something like
that in which case you would learn that
hey being in this position actually
generates even worse observations in
which case that would be a matrix
learning the other way you can do it is
by somehow involved somehow model
learning the actual preference
distribution itself which you can do but
it's a little bit kind of beyond the
scope of this that's what I just yeah
yeah you can you can fiddle with C but
um learning C is a little bit more
complicated and but you can certainly
fit C values like we do right to see
what C is for each person for each
possible observation so so yes yeah I
mean hopefully hopefully want to get to
some of the learning stuff that'll be a
little bit ok so here so preferences
here so your your C vectors so I'm just
starting out saying you know these are
just a bunch of zeros for each possible
observation modality and then I'm saying
okay so for the first one right the one
where I'm observing what the stimuli are
that I observe at the end of each trial
these have a particular value assigned
to them at time point two right so
column one is time point one column two
is time going to and I'm parameterizing
these so here I'm saying that the value
of negative image is just this parameter
neg underscore IMG and then positive
underscore IMG and then this one is the
same parameter again but plus two times
whatever my subjective point value is
and then so on and so forth so there's
two parameters I'm fitting here there's
those three there's negative image
positive image and point value and but
as you'll see what we actually end up
doing to make this invertible is you
just fix the positive image value at 0
this
kind of like an anchor value and then
the other two get adjusted around that
so if I were to choose the parameter
value of negative one for image zero for
positive image and point value equals
subjective point value equals one then
that's what the C vector would look like
it'd be negative one for the negative
image observation two for the positive
image plus two one for negative image
plus two three and five so this is just
saying how much the agent for first one
over the other but again I mean this is
just arbitrary based on the app based on
the values of the parameters that I
picked but we're gonna fit those and
figure out which one's best reproduce
each participant's behavior okay and so
then the last part of the model then
right as you have yes sorry so so each
column is a time point yeah
so a time point one it's just always
gonna be in the starting position so it
doesn't matter their time point to it
prefers its preference distribution
looks like that or higher equals more
positive so then II like I said we're
not assuming any kind of habits here so
he's just a flat distribution with ones
over each possible policy and we have to
set some value for for beta so for prior
policy precision in this case we're
fitting that as a parameter as well so I
just put it as an example you just buy
beta equals four but but this is
something we're fitting so we're gonna
get a value for this for each person um
and that's really it then you know
you've defined well so T is just the
number of time points so just T equals
two in this case but so you've defined
each of these things you just throw them
into a structure that's labeled little
MDP and these three I've commented out
because as I'll go into if you want to
if you want to include learning then you
also include you can also include a
little a little be your little D or a
little C or a little e actually but I
just in practice don't use this much but
these are all commented out because
we're not
learning isn't happening we're not
separating out the the actual generative
process from the agents model and and
again beta adjust equals MVP beta equals
beta here which we said in the example
being four there are these other two
that are worth mentioning so MVP alpha
is a essentially a an inverse
temperature parameter it's like you can
think about it as just encoding some
some level of like behavioral noise or
motor stochasticity so I think kind of
like shaky hand you know when you're
pushing a button there is always a
little bit of that in human behavior and
then Etta is learning rate um basically
governs how much of a count you actually
tech you know tack on every time you
have a new observation but again that
doesn't matter in this case because
we're not including learning so once you
have all that then you you know say your
parameter values for a simulation and
then you plug the hole MDP thing into
this very very dense and opaque function
that carla wrote called the SPM - MVP w
or underscore vb underscore x script and
it will take your model run it and the
the message passing algorithms that
minimise free energy and it will spit
out the results what the agent shows and
so this is an example of the kind of
simulation outputs that you'll get
there's different plotting scripts
depending on what you want to look at
but in this case the plotting script for
a single trial is this MVP underscore vb
underscore trial function and these are
all just built into SPM in the de m
toolbox so they're all just as long as
you have SPM twelve-year it's all there
and so the way that you can kind of read
this is the darker the color the higher
the probability so in this case the
stronger the belief of the agent and the
little cyan dots represent kind of the
ground truth so in this case the agent
believed that
action 10 so moving to position 9 was
the best move to make at the end of the
day and that is what it shows this is
its beliefs about position so it
believes that at time 1 it was in
position 1 and believes at time 2 it was
a position 10 sir state 10 state state
factor 1 level 10 so position 9 and that
was true and it believes that it was in
the first condition the avoid threat
condition so more or less it just moved
all the way toward the Sun because that
was the that's the thing that made the
most sense to do because it was correct
about what condition it was in now like
like you were saying if Lawrence if if
it had some uncertainty about what
condition it was in then it wouldn't
have been near that confident but were
the right place to move with that right
so this could have been more kind of
gray I got more kind of diffused
probability distribution over different
states then you'd get different behavior
and ignore that that doesn't really mean
anything this is just saying how it's
this is just the posterior probability
over policy so it's how the policies
essentially how confidence in policies
change over time so this is saying it
was before it saw what position and
condition it was in
it was completely uncertain about which
of the nine possible policies it should
choose and then after it saw the
position and condition it jumped up to
being very confident in just the policy
of going to the ninth position that
update in confidence from from before to
after seeing the position and
conditioned stimuli corresponds in the
neural process theory to getting a
little kind of bump in dopamine so
that's where that that kind of change in
policy precision is what uh what you
would simulate as kind of physic
dopamine response if you were going to
try to use this in like a model based
fMRI analysis to see if you could you
know throw that into throw that like
trial by trial prediction to like say
like an fMRI simulation and see if you
can actually track things that look like
they plausibly correspond to
dopamine sending or receiving brain
regions for example Phillips
quarterbacks actually done that in a
paper from a couple years ago and showed
really nice ventral tegmental area
activation as well as cortical
activation and a bunch of known
dopaminergic target regions so
well I mean basically it just it just
like it's just very confident in what
the best decision is right so i mean ii
ii did because remember in this
condition this is the avoid threat
condition it's basically there's a bad
thing and there's a good thing there's
no conflict there's nothing so it's just
fully rational like there is no
uncertainty at all about you should just
move toward the thing that's gonna be
good it would be different you know in
the different conditions especially if
beta was a higher number because it
would have a lot more uncertainty so
anyway so then here at the bottom this
is showing the actual observations and
the colors here correspond to the
relative preferences and the preference
distribution so basically it doesn't
care what conditions it's in or doesn't
care what position it's in but it does
have interesting preference differences
over the observations it can observe the
outcomes that can observe at time two
and so in this case the distribution
looks like that and what it actually
observed was this guy which I'm pretty
sure is just the positive stimulus or
something so that is more or less how it
works beginning to end you can then you
can then run that repeatedly to get
multiple trials so in this case for the
task in question
we have sixty trials I'm in total and so
you can run the thing under different
parameter values and have the agent do
it 60 times in a row then you can get a
sense of what the actual behavior across
the task would look like under different
parameter values and then you can do
that a bunch of times and our different
parameter values until you find the set
of parameter values that best matches a
given participants behavior and then
those estimated values we'd actually use
in further individual difference
analyses and the way to do that or at
least the way that we've done it is
using this variational base function
that's also just built into SPM that
minimizes variational
via variational Bayes it's this SPM
underscore and LSI underscore Newton
function and and so what you need to do
is you just take an agent's observations
from the actual task and what the
actions they chose work on the task
those go into these U and Y variables
and and then you have to set some priors
for what you think good kind of starting
parameter about good plausible starting
parameter values might be for anybody
and then what it does is it will just
start with those priors and then
iteratively adjust them around until it
finds values that minimize the log
likelihood ie maximize free energy ie
produce the behavior that's most
consistent with the actual agents
behavior or the actual participants
behavior um but doing it this way when
you start with particular prior values
this particular algorithm it penalize
--is moving the parameter estimates
farther from the prior values that you
set and that's a way of avoiding
overfitting the idea is the farther you
need to move parameters from the prior
value that you thought was plausible the
more kind of the more overfit something
might look so by penalizing that you're
it's a way of preventing overfitting so
it's finding the best fit parameters
without moving them too far from the
priors you set and so in practice we do
that and it will look like this where
over time so is it with each iteration
it will give you a log evidence or
energy and over time what you hope to
see is that this goes up every time it
eventually converges on the parameter
values that fit pretty well with the
agents behavior and so in this case you
can just see this is just showing how
the how the parameter value has changed
from the prior values and this is
probably a clearer depiction of this
where for the negative image I started
it at a value of
one which would be negative in the model
and the posterior was less for point
value it went up and forbade it went up
and in that case the direction in which
those move was consistent with what the
actual values were that I plugged into
the simulation which is what you want to
see to know that your models recoverable
so so I can actually just yes
well I mean it's just it's just the
depending on the sign right like in in
engineering a lot of times it is cast as
maximizing yeah I know I agree you can
think about this
yes it's identical - yeah yeah right and
that is one of those things that yeah
Karl Karl could have been clearer about
when you draw these chips but right yeah
yeah yeah hmm sure
no and that's a--that's a good point I
am that I should have mentioned and
didn't um that yeah I mean it's just the
point is yes that it is converging to an
optimal value so just to actually show
you a little bit and the actual so here
is so now if you know you guys will not
look at it here is the actual this AAC
underscore model underscore example so
this is the full script that I just kind
of went through with snapshots piece by
piece you know so clear I'll close all I
just set the random number generator to
shuffle just so it doesn't produce the
exact same thing every time I set my
parameter values to particular violet
values um this is just again exactly
just piece by piece what I showed you um
I don't think I really left anything out
and one thing I guess worth mentioning
is is that you can either specify
policies in terms of U or V you as if
you want policies to be shallow which
means they only want one step ahead and
V is in practice if you want the
policies to be deep so the agent whoops
saw ahead all the way up to the end of
it ahead all the way till the end of the
trial you can specify it as V even if
your trial if it's only one step though
which I which I am kind of like to do
because if you specify it as use and it
won't spit out the dopamine simulations
but okay so then anyway I mean this is
this is just basically giving it labels
giving the plotting routine labels this
checking thing is just a thing that
helps you know you didn't mess up
something you didn't write something
inconsistent in your generative model
before you run it and then you run it
then this is the VB trial plot then this
is just a couple other plots that you
can generate the curls written plotting
scripts for and then here is if I want
to run more than one trial then I can
just expand the MVP and that I made so
it's
replicated over several trials and then
you can just run that whole thing again
with the same function and then their
plotting routines for looking at
behavior across trials and you know so
if I do this it's run one of these
normally it's very fast but on this
computer it's kind of slow so I probably
won't run the group one but but here you
go this is the s I mean this is
basically the exact same thing is the
one I showed you but and this is a
another plot that I'm probably not gonna
go through this it's not all that
interesting in the context of this task
but they're just it's just other
depictions of things in the model or
what the neural process theory would
predict but if you want to know more
about this kind of thing I can we can
talk about it later it's just going to
be more confusing for now I think but if
if this if it wasn't so well maybe I can
do it I was gonna say it's going to say
it might take too long to run the
multiple trials version but it's
probably worth you guys seeing a little
bit what it looks like so more or less
this is just so this is showing five
trials and these are just different
sorts of plots that I'm more or less
just encode the free-energy expected
utility of the observations on each
trial and they're just kin different
kind of ways of coding the same thing is
in the the single trial plots but just
over multiple trials and again if you
want to know details about what each of
those mean then I can I can them we can
talk about it individually later it's
not that but important for now but in
the and then in the second script that I
gave you guys which is this inversion
example script this has everything you
need to actually do the parameter
estimation model inversion that I that I
showed you the example of where the
thing will converge on the optimal for
energy value it's also probably a little
involved to go into in detail but here I
just set the number of trials
and then I set the parameter values that
I to fixed values that I don't want to
estimate then I set the some values that
don't actually they're that well in this
case I'm setting the values the true
parameter values for the simulation I'm
going to run I just kind of specify them
here so that it will spit them out at
the end so I can compare them to the
actual model estimates and this is just
putting together the U and why all this
is just putting together the U and Y
vectors that are going to be the
observations and the actions that gets
fed into the estimation routine and then
down here more or less I just specify
which of the parameters I actually want
to estimate and then all of that goes
into this DCM structure along with the U
and Y which are the stimuli and the
actions and then you run this and then
you turn that into you take that DCM and
you run it through the actual a it's the
inversion script that I wrote which is
just this function that's appended below
and this is the one that in turn you set
the priors for so this is basically
saying if I want to I want to say that
my prior for beta is one and I put that
in log space to keep it positive so that
during estimation it doesn't become a
negative number because beta can't be a
negative number and then same thing for
point value and for any of these others
but it will only catch them if I say I
want to estimate these so in this case
it'll estimate beta a negative image and
point value and so here the priors that
put R yes mm-hmm
and yeah so it will so basically what
I'll do is I just I just exponentiate it
down here so it stays nonzero it's
literally just a trick so it never
becomes negative during the estimation
but it so anyway so you do that and then
at the end of the day it goes into this
guy which is the actual estimation
routine that runs the variational base
and then you also need a likelihood
function which is written here basically
it just takes you start out with an L
value of 0 and then it will repeatedly
just add the previous likelihood value
to the log probability of the basically
the probability that the model assigns
to the action that the agent actually
chose and so it tries to maximize that
over over iterations what do you say oh
it's just it's just adding a little kind
of small number to make sure that it
never becomes 0 and then this is just
reproducing the generative model that we
already walked through but just as a
function and then that's it so you can
toy around with this obviously I've
skipped through a little kind of just
procedural things to just assigning
different variables to other things just
for sake of time but if I run this then
it will simulate 60 trials and then it
will try to fit them and I probably will
take way too long to even show you any
of it but give it a sec well that's
that's just a single trial results yeah
give it like another I don't know see it
produced its first I likelihood estimate
of negative 59 and it all so basically
it'll it'll bounce around like small
fluctuation
around that number for a certain number
of iterations basically until it's kind
of tried out little adjustments to each
of the parameters and then it'll jump on
the next iteration to whatever goes down
the gradient but I'm not going to not
gonna run that the whole way because no
way anytime so okay so anyway so that's
so that's kind of beginning to end
thoroughly through one task which Artie
I realize it's probably a lot there were
you know maybe we don't have to go into
as much detail and the other ones but I
mean another task that we were kind of
excited about that's like an even kind
of simpler model is this model that we
built of an interceptive awareness task
and this is meant to kind of capture
this idea that a lot of people in
computational psychiatry are now kind of
like this idea that what might be going
wrong is something about precision
estimates assigned to afferent signals
from the body and the way that
contributes to either representing an
understanding bodily States and also
subsequent viscera motor regulation and
so but no one's actually kind of try to
explicitly show in any kind of model
that different clinical groups actually
do a sign look like they assign
different precision estimates to after
an intercept of signals and so we
thought we'd give it a go and so we use
this kind of really simple heart be
tapping task and the idea is literally
just for sixty seconds we just say tap a
button whenever you feel your heart beat
and then we simultaneously record EKGs
and pulse transit time and things like
that
so we know when their actual heart beat
was and what the soonest is that they
would have felt it and so we did this
into three conditions plus a control
condition one where we said just guess
do your best
another where we said don't guess only
press the button if you're totally sure
I mean a third one where
the no guessing stipulation was still in
place but we also did an intercepted
perturbation where we had them hold
their breath with the hope of kind of
amplifying the afferent signal and the
reason that's important is because most
people at rest have a really really
terrible conscious interoception only
about 35% of people in these tasks
typically show greater than chance
performance when they're trying to like
indicate when they feel their heartbeat
so to really get things off of floor
values in a way that would be meaningful
you probably have to do some kind of
perturbation where you're getting the
kind of variance that will be more
interesting but you had to like control
right for like something like they're
guessing rate and also something like
how a conservative or liberal they're
being and so we did that again we did
that in that same sample um but in this
case we actually just did to try it we
just decided to divide it up a little
more fine grain so it's healthy people
people with depression and people with
anxiety people with anxiety and
depression eating disorders we have like
18 people and then the substance use
group so it's a pretty broad clinical
group this is the way they set up the
model it looks more complicated than it
is more or less what we did is we just
divided we took their actual cardiac
events and we divided and then we added
200 milliseconds from false transit time
and then you we just basically divided
the epochs in half so that between
heartbeats if you tapped in the first
half of the time before the next
heartbeat then that counted as tapping
during systole
otherwise it was tapping as a day under
diastole and so that's it
so the observations here were just
assists elite or a diastole which was
just based on their EKG political
strands of time and then the other set
of observations is just the conjunction
and of whether they tapped and assisted
ly didn't happen assistly
tap the no delay no tap than that
these are this is uh considered the
afferent input that the brain is getting
from their from the body so does their
it's equivalent to like a visual
stimulus but just coming up from their
heart and and then this then is just
basically encoding what they want right
they're gonna prefer to tap when these
assist aliy to tap and to observe that
they tapped and observe assisted lee and
not observe a no tap innocently etc
right so just just true positives false
positives true later guys from it's your
positive sure negatives false positives
false negatives and and and so what we
fit here is then just um
so these see values essentially how much
they wanted to observe tapping and
systole and the inverse for no tapping
in systole and and the same thing for
diastole and tapping versus no tapping
and and it's a little bit hard to
understand intuitively but what this
ends up acting as is just a bias for
tapping versus not having so the the
higher the if you look at if you just
take the PMT um value which is
essentially how much they prefer to not
get a false positive versus PT which is
how much they what the magnitude is that
they prefer not getting a false negative
then again Jeff it just ends up this
ends up just giving you essentially a
metric of their bias against tapping and
so just it's just kind of a measure of
you know or the kind of person that
likes to tap a lot or not very much it's
kind of like I kind of treat
conservatism about it as that um the
other kind of thing that you can do and
again this isn't initially all that
intuitive but if you just take the
average of those two so they're the
average magnitude of their preference of
the Preferences they have for both of
those things then if that's a positive
value then what that means is that what
that means is that they actually had a
strong preference to tap after
a heartbeat whereas if that if that is
negative then it means that they were
actually an anticipate or they reliably
tried to tap right before heart rate so
you can kind of differentiate between
anticipatory versus reactive strategies
okay and and then but the most
interesting one that we wanted to
estimate was interoceptive precision so
essentially the precision of the mapping
from systole and diastole x' to felt
heart beats or not heart beats and where
the other where the controllable hidden
state factor was choosing to tap or not
tap right so the higher the IP value
equals more precise and then I already
explained this kind of tapping no
tapping bias thing and so this is the
kind of thing that we find so this is
the bias against tapping measure and as
you can see as you would as you would
hope that this value is much higher in
the no testing condition and the grethel
condition and then in the guessing
conditions people are a lot more
conservative and when they choose to tap
in these two which is exactly what you
would expect this is just a Kanaka
parameter validation kind of thing and
the sensory precision is really high in
the control tone condition sorry I
didn't explain that basically the
control condition is they just kept
hearing a tone and they had to tap
whenever they heard a tone and so
precision estimates are really high for
auditory precision in the tone condition
and they're super super low you know
except for some people to look like
outliers any others and for the
anticipate versus react thing the
average of the see magnitudes what you
get is basically a big chunk of people
that are around zero which basically
means they were really inconsistent and
they're tapping which is just correlated
with a sensory precision but then you
have a good chunk of people that are on
either end that are kind of reliable
anticipators versus reliable reactors
and so you can think some is like
relying a lot more on prior expectations
and others relying a lot on warrants
than 3-input and so in terms of further
parameter validation we just add we just
looked at a bunch of different things so
pulsed transit time a number of
heartbeats a heart rate I'm for each
person self-reported difficulty of the
task self-reported confidence that they
did it right
self-reported felt heartbeat intensity
and then age and BMI so body mass index
and there's all things that influence
cardiac perception and so what we found
it's kind of cool is that for
interoceptive precision and it was
positively associated with confidence
and intensity even in the guessing
condition and whereas in the no guessing
in the breath would condition both where
this conservatism was higher the bias
against tapping was associated in the
directions you'd expect with difficulty
and confidence in intensity and those
are actually pretty similar and it's
nothing else all that interesting
what's kinda interesting even in the
tone condition when that precision is
essentially maximal
you do get this kind of age difference
in whether people are anticipated versus
reactors which was kind of interesting
and there weren't really all that many
interesting differences or any
interesting relationships here basically
sensory precision in one condition
didn't really map all that well the
sensory precision and other conditions
between the no guessing condition in the
breath old condition there was more
similarity and sensory precision but not
that much biases against tapping was
actually looked like it was kind of more
trade ish across conditions for people
and but the the interesting result is
that the main interesting result is that
when you look across groups for our
interceptive precision and estimates
they the healthy controls do have
significantly higher interceptive
precision than all of the clinical
groups and the any other interesting
effect that we saw was that actually
medication status strongly blunted
interceptive precision so if you were on
any kind of psychiatric medication your
interoceptive precision was much less
and anyway doesn't look like we have
time but I could have gone through
basically how we specify the model for
that and the only thing probably worth
mentioning is the way that we specified
interoceptive precision so in this case
the way to fit this kind of precision
parameter is you start just with
diastole and systole mapping as an
identity matrix to feeling a heartbeat
and not but then you can pass this thing
through a softmax function with a
particular temperature parameter so it
ends up happening is if this PA or
intercept of precision is high it ends
up looking like an identity matrix
whereas the lower you may have to get
this thing the more imprecise it ends up
looking right so if person has values
down here that means that the signal
they get from systole and diastole
provides a lot less precise evidence for
the presence of a beat or note B and yes
yeah I mean and again I can go through
you know all this with you guys
more you know just in person one of one
at a time or whatever if you guys want
to but these are you know I just kind of
listed the whole bottle up here in case
you guys want to look at it but the the
way you estimate parameters is the same
definitely won't have time to go into
the UM band a reward learning version or
our or our structure learning stuff but
hopefully this was helpful and Casper's
gonna have a bunch of time tomorrow to
take us further so yeah any any
questions or anything like that I mean
obviously it would ask you something
away
[Music]
you
[Applause]
[Music]